### Wenxin Ye

San Francisco, CA 94132 • 415-888-1130 • whenxin.ye@gmail.com • Linkedin.com/in/wenxin-ye/ • www.wenxinye.info

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Marketing professional with 2 years' working experience in SEO, SEM, social media, content, e-mail, and influencer marketing. Met 130% of user acquisition goal through managing multi-channels. Improved 25% customer service efficiency by systemizing the communication process. A team player with people management skills and entrepreneurial spirit. Looking to leverage proven leadership and marketing skills for a fast-growing company as digital marketing specialist.

#### **EXPERIENCE HIGHLIGHTS**

## **BOOSTINSIDER INC, an influencer marketing agency and software company**. October 2017 – Present **Digital Marketing Specialist**

Manage 40% of company client accounts. Plan and execute influencer marketing campaigns for global clients. Develop strategies for both paid and organic marketing channels with the goal of user acquisition. Lead a content team of 2. Served as the point of contact for PR and partnership companies.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Saved more than 60% of cost for clients' influencer marketing campaigns by negotiating terms with influencers.
- Ranked image from no presence to No.1. by performing SEO through establishing editorial calendar and building backlinks.
- Increased 50% web traffic and 20% user signups by strategizing and optimizing paid search campaigns including Google Adwords and Quora Ads. Report to C-level execs on weekly-basis.
- Cumulatively generated 200+ shares and 60k+ article views in 2 months and increased 10% of total user signups by developing and executing blog content strategies.

## **TOLOCAL, INC, a Facebook lead generation company.** September 2017 – October 2017 **Paid Display Specialist**

Contributed revenue to the growth of the business by generating and converting Facebook leads to sales.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Hit the ROI benchmark in just 1 month (usually 2 month) by performing A/B testing, tracking and optimizing Facebook campaign performance on a daily basis.
- Converted 10% of leads to sales by using Mailchimp to execute email campaigns.

# **GOPACKUP, INC, an online travel marketplace.** May 2017 – August 2017 **Social Media Marketing Intern**

Optimized social media campaigns by analyzing user behavior data on Google Analytics. Conducted keyword research to identified customer trends. Supported business development by coordinating tasks among design and technical teams.

#### **Key Accomplishments:**

- Increased web traffic by 50% by planning and executing creative marketing campaign as well as developing campaign timeline and collaborating with cross-functional teams.
- Sourced social media influencers to further campaigns by using Followerwonk and Netlytic.
- Optimized functions of apps and websites for outside agents by collaborating with cross-functional teams.

#### COMMUNITY LEADERSHIP

## **ZAIGEZAIGU GALA.ORG, a volunteer community hosted by high-tech company employees.** CA, Nov 2018 – Present **Marketing Manager**

Built brand online presence from ground up. Recruit and manage a team of 15 and oversee all aspect of online and offline marketing activities. Working closely with event production team, setting clear P0, P1 deadlines and success hurdles.

#### **EDUCATION**

Gary J. Sbona Business Honors | **Bachelor of Arts in Marketing** | San Jose State University, 2017 GPA 3.48

<u>Coursework</u>: Marketing Research, Quant Bus Analysis

<u>Certificates, Tools & Skillsets</u>: Google Ads Search Certification, Hootsuite Platform Certification; Advanced Excel, Google Analytics, Google Search Console, Salesforce, Jira, InDesign, Al, WordPress; People management, B2B Sales, Copywriting, Customer Service.